1000memories.com 2013-08-09

# Privacy | 1000memories

The privacy of you and your family and friends is important to 1000memories. You can find our full privacy policy below. Our guiding approach is that you should control your privacy. We will always do our best to equip you with the tools to adjust and tailor your privacy as you see fit.

## Privacy Policy: By using or accessing 1000memories, you agree to this statement.

Date of last revision: March 14th, 2012.

This policy contains nine sections:

  1. 1\. Introduction
  2. 2\. Information We Receive
  3. 3\. Sharing information on 1000memories
  4. 4\. Information You Share With Third Parties
  5. 5\. How We Use Your Information
  6. 6\. How We Share Information
  7. 7\. How You Can Change or Remove Information
  8. 8\. How We Protect Information
  9. 9\. Other Terms

### 1\. Introduction

Questions. If you have any questions or concerns about our privacy policy, contact our privacy team through one of the following:

  * \- by email at ancestrywrsupport@mailmw.custhelp.com
  * \- by mail at 153 Townsend St, Suite 800, San Francisco, CA 94025 USA.

Parental participation. We strongly recommend that minors 13 years of age or younger ask their parents for permission before sending any information about themselves to anyone over the Internet and we encourage parents to teach their children about safe internet use practices.

### 2\. Information We Receive

### Information you provide to us:

Information About Yourself. When you sign up for 1000memories you may provide us with your name and email. Once you register, you will also be able to add a picture of yourself and you can provide other information about yourself, about people, relationships, dates, and places.

Content. One of the primary reasons people use 1000memories is to share content with others. Examples include when you upload, import or tag a photo and make a comment. If you do not want us to store metadata associated with content you share on 1000memories (such as photos), please remove the metadata before uploading the content.

Friend Information. We offer contact importer tools to help you upload your friends’ addresses so that you can find your friends and family on 1000memories, and invite your contacts who do not have 1000memories accounts to join. If you give us your password to retrieve those contacts, we will not store your password after you have uploaded your contacts’ information.

### Information we collect when you interact with 1000memories:

Site activity information. We keep track of some of the actions you take on 1000memories, such as adding friends and family, uploading a photo, commenting and "liking" content. In some cases you are also taking an action when you provide information or content to us. For example, if you share a photo, in addition to storing the actual content you uploaded, we might log the fact that you shared it.

Access Device and Browser Information. When you access 1000memories from a computer, mobile phone, or other device, we may collect information from that device about your browser type, location, and IP address, as well as the pages you visit.

Cookie Information. We use "cookies" (small pieces of data we store for an extended period of time on your computer, mobile phone, or other device) to make 1000memories easier to use and to protect both you and 1000memories. You can remove or block cookies using the settings in your browser, but in some cases that may impact your ability to use 1000memories.

### Information we receive from third parties:

Information from other users. We may collect information about you from other 1000memories users, such as when a family member or friend tags you in a photo, or indicates a relationship with you.

### 3\. Sharing information on 1000memories.

This section explains how your privacy settings work, and how your information is shared on 1000memories. You should always consider your privacy settings before sharing information on 1000memories.

Profile privacy on 1000memories. 1000memories is designed to make it easy for you to find and connect with others. We offer two privacy settings for your profile information on 1000memories. Public allows other users to find your profile using the search feature on 1000memories. Private hides your profile from search results.

Profile privacy on public search engines. We offer two privacy settings for your profile information on search engines. Public allows others to find your profile using Google and other search engines. Private hides your profile from search results and we will add the "noindex" metatag to your profile. Sometimes there may be a lag before specific search engines recognize this and remove you from their indexes.

Contact Information. Your contact information will not be shared with anyone unless you elect to do so or order third party services through 1000memories. For example, if you purchase professional scanning services from our partner, ScanCafe, your contact information is shared with ScanCafe. We require third party services to respect your privacy, and your agreement with that third party will control how it can use, store, and transfer that information.

Shoebox privacy. We offer two privacy settings for your shoeboxes. Private shoeboxes can only be viewed by members invited by the shoebox author. Public shoeboxes can be viewed by any 1000memories user or non-user. In all cases, only invited members can add, edit, or comment on photos in a shoebox.

Content privacy. In addition to our shoebox privacy settings, you can choose to make your photo uploads and photos that you are tagged in public or private. Public photos will be viewable to all 1000memories users and non-users. Private photos will be only be viewable to you and content authors.

Other. Here are some other things to remember:

  * Some of the content you share and the actions you take will show up on your family members' and friends’ shoeboxes.
  * If another user tags you in a photo, you can remove the tag.
  * Even after you remove information from your profile or delete your account, copies of that information may remain viewable elsewhere to the extent it has been shared with others, it was otherwise distributed pursuant to your privacy settings, or it was copied or stored by other users.
  * You understand that information might be reshared or copied by other users.
  * Certain types of communications that you send to other users cannot be removed.
  * When you post information or comment on another user’s content, that information will be subject to that piece of content's privacy settings.

Minors. We reserve the right to add special protections for minors (such as to provide them with an age-appropriate experience) and place restrictions on the ability of adults to share and connect with minors, recognizing this may provide minors a more limited experience on 1000memories.

### 4\. Information You Share With Third Parties.

Links. When you click on links on 1000memories you may leave our site. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites, and we encourage you to read their privacy statements.

### 5\. How We Use Your Information

We use the information we collect to try to provide a safe, efficient, and customized experience. Here are some of the details on how we do that:

To manage the service. We use the information we collect to provide our services and features to you, to measure and improve those services and features, and to provide you with customer support. We use the information to prevent potentially illegal activities, and to enforce our Terms of Service. We also use a variety of technological systems to detect and address anomalous activity and screen content to prevent abuse such as spam. These efforts may on occasion result in a temporary or permanent suspension or termination of some functions for some users.

To contact you. We may contact you with service-related announcements from time to time. You may opt out of all communications except essential updates on your user account settings page. We may include content you see on 1000memories in the emails we send to you.

To supplement your shoeboxes. We may use information about you that we collect from other 1000memories users to supplement your profile (such as when you are tagged in a photo). In such cases we generally give you the ability to remove the content (such as allowing you to remove a photo tag of you).

To make suggestions. We use your information, including the addresses you import through our contact importers, to make suggestions to you and other users on 1000memories. For example, if another user imports the same email address as you do, we may suggest that you add each other as friends. Similarly, if one of your friends uploads a picture of you, we may suggest that your friend tag you in the picture. We do this by comparing your friend’s pictures to information we’ve put together from the photos you’ve been tagged in. We may also suggest that you use certain tools and features based on what your friends have used.

To help your friends find you. We allow other users to use contact information they have about you, such as your email address, to find you, including through contact importers and search.

Downloadable Software. Certain downloadable software applications and applets that we offer, such as our photo uploaders, transmit data to us. We may not make a formal disclosure if we believe our collection of and use of the information is the obvious purpose of the application, such as the fact that we receive photos when you use our photo uploader. If we believe it is not obvious that we are collecting or using such information, we will make a disclosure to you the first time you provide the information to us so that you can decide whether you want to use that feature.

### 6\. How We Share Information

1000memories is about sharing information with others — family, friends and people in your communities — while providing you with privacy settings that you can use to restrict other users from accessing some of your information. We share your information with third parties when we believe the sharing is permitted by you, reasonably necessary to offer our services, reasonably necessary to offer third-party services you order through 1000memories, or when legally required to do so. For example:

When you invite a friend to join. When you ask us to invite a friend to join 1000memories, we will send your friend a message on your behalf using your name. The invitation may also contain information about other users your friend might know. We may also send up to two reminders to them in your name. You can see who has accepted your invitations, send reminders, and delete your friends’ email addresses on your followers page.

To help your friends find you. By default, we make certain information you have posted to your profile available in search results on 1000memories to help your family and friends find you. This information can be adjusted using your privacy settings.

To give search engines access to publicly available information. To help record extraordinary stories, photos and the pieces of content shared on our site we share content that is accessible to everybody with search engines to help others looking for the same relatives to find this. This information is still protected by our privacy settings (which you can adjust) and any IP rights you have.

To help improve or promote our service. Sometimes we share aggregated information with third parties to help improve or promote our service. But we only do so in such a way that no individual user can be identified or linked to any specific action or information.

To provide you with services. We may provide information to service providers that help us bring you the services we offer. For example, we may use third parties to help host our website, send out email updates about 1000memories. These service providers may have access to your personal information for use for a limited time, but when this occurs we implement reasonable contractual and technical protections to limit their use of that information to helping us provide the service.

To advertise our services. We may ask advertisers outside of 1000memories to display ads promoting our services. We may ask them to deliver those ads based on the presence of a cookie, but in doing so will not share any other information with the advertiser.

To respond to legal requests and prevent harm. We may disclose information pursuant to subpoenas, court orders, or other requests (including criminal and civil matters) if we have a good faith belief that the response is required by law. This may include respecting requests from jurisdictions outside of the United States where we have a good faith belief that the response is required by law under the local laws in that jurisdiction, apply to users from that jurisdiction, and are consistent with generally accepted international standards. We may also share information when we have a good faith belief it is necessary to prevent fraud or other illegal activity, to prevent imminent bodily harm, or to protect ourselves and you from people violating our Statement of Rights and Responsibilities. This may include sharing information with other companies, lawyers, courts or other government entities.

Transfer in the Event of Sale or Change of Control. If the ownership of all or substantially all of our business changes, we may transfer your information to the new owner so that the service can continue to operate. In such a case, your information would remain subject to the promises made in any pre-existing Privacy Policy.

### 7\. How You Can Change or Remove Information

Editing your profile. You may change or remove your profile information at any time by going to your Shoebox page and clicking the cog next to your name. Information will be updated immediately.

Delete uploaded contacts. If you use our contact importer to upload addresses, you can later delete those connections on your family and friends page.

Deactivating or deleting your account. If you want to stop using your account we may deactivate it or delete it. When you deactivate an account, no user will be able to see it, but it will not be deleted. We save your profile information (connections, photos, etc.) in case you later decide to reactivate your account. Many users deactivate their accounts for temporary reasons and in doing so are asking us to maintain their information until they return to 1000memories. You will still have the ability to reactivate your account and restore your profile in its entirety.

Limitations on removal. Even after you remove information from your profile or delete your account, copies of that information may remain viewable elsewhere to the extent it has been shared with others, it was otherwise distributed pursuant to your privacy settings, or it was copied or stored by other users. Additionally, we may retain certain information to prevent identity theft and other misconduct even if deletion has been requested.

Backup copies. Removed and deleted information may persist in backup copies, but will not be available to others.

Non-user contact information. If a user provides your email address to us, and you are not a 1000memories user but you want us to delete your address, you can do so by emailing ancestrywrsupport@mailmw.custhelp.com. However, that request will only apply to addresses we have at the time of the request and not to any addresses that users provide to us later.

### 8\. How We Protect Information

We do our best to keep your information secure, but we need your help.

Steps we take to keep your information secure. We keep your account information on a secured server behind a firewall. When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card numbers and passwords), we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). We also use automated and social measures to enhance security, such as analyzing account behavior for fraudulent or otherwise anomalous behavior, may limit use of site features in response to possible signs of abuse, may remove inappropriate content or links to illegal content, and may suspend or disable accounts for violations of our Terms of Service.

Risks inherent in sharing information. Although we allow you to set privacy options that limit access to your information, please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. We cannot control the actions of other users with whom you share your information. We cannot guarantee that only authorized persons will view your information. We cannot ensure that information you share on 1000memories will not become publicly available. We are not responsible for third party circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures on 1000memories. You can reduce these risks by using common sense security practices such as choosing a strong password, using different passwords for different services, and using up to date antivirus software.

Report Violations. You should report any security violations to us at ancestrywrsupport@mailmw.custhelp.com.

### 9\. Other Terms

Changes. We may change this Privacy Policy pursuant to the procedures outlined in the 1000memories Terms of Service. Unless stated otherwise, our current privacy policy applies to all information that we have about you and your account. If we make changes to this Privacy Policy we will notify you by publication here. If the changes are material, we will provide you additional, prominent notice as appropriate under the circumstances.

Consent to Collection and Processing in the United States. By using 1000memories, you consent to having your personal data transferred to and processed in the United States.

We are always looking for ways to work with our users to make our privacy clearer, fairer and better. Please get in touch if you have any comments or suggestions: ancestrywrsupport@mailmw.custhelp.com
